Bulut Karakaya

bulutk@gmail.com | www.bulutk.com

Phone: +44 (7470) 890039 | Skype: bulutkarakaya

Career Objective

I'm an ambitious gameplay programmer with 12+ years of experience. My focus areas are core gameplay and networking using Unity and Unreal engines. I co-founded two indie game studios before and currently working to create inspiring games in the UK. My objective is to find ways to merge my interest in machine learning with game development to open new possibilities.

Work Experience	
March 2021 - Present	Lead Programmer – ustwo Games, U.K.
	• Technical lead on an unannounced game.
	• Line manager for 3 senior programmers.
July 2018 - March 2021	Senior Gameplay Programmer - Jagex Ltd, Cambridge, U.K.
	• Worked on an unannounced Action-RPG game using Unreal Engine 4, C++.
M 1 2017 T 2010	• Worked on core combat, player and AI navigation as well as high-level networking.
March 2017 – June 2018	Lead Unity Programmer – Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland • Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android using Unity, C#
	• Line manager for a senior and a mid-level programmer.
Oct 2016 - March 2017	Senior Unity Programmer – Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
Oct 2010 Water 2017	• Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command , for IOS and Android using Unity, C#
Nov 2014 - May 2016	Co-founder / Technical Director – Pera Games, Istanbul, Turkey
·	• Created Overfall a rogue-like RPG title for Steam using Unity, C#
	• Responsible for all the programming and creating the tools for our non-technical team to create characters, spells
	environments and encounters without programmer help.
	• Launched the game on Steam, %93 positive feedback at the end of the first month.
	• Presented Overfall at Unite'16 as a showcase game.
March 2014 - Sept 2014	Project Partner – GriPati Digital Entertainment, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Created Egg Fight a multiplayer fast-paced fighting game for IOS and Android using Unity, C#
Jan 2013 – Feb 2014	 Responsible for all the programming and partial game design. Co-founder / Technical Director – Tart Games, Istanbul, Turkey
Jan 2013 – Feb 2014	• Created Kixel a multiplayer 3d soccer game for Facebook and IOS using Unity, C#
	• Responsible for most of the gameplay programming and leading a team of 6 people.
Aug 2012 - April 2013	Software Engineer – Tart New Media, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Responsible for optimising and developing the backend of gamification engine.
	• Line manager for 2 junior programmers.
Sept 2010 - Dec 2011	Gameplay Programmer – Gravi, Istanbul, Turkey
	 Worked on Gravi Floor, an interactive playground which features various mini-games.
June 2009 - Aug 2009	Prototype Intern – Stupid Fun Club, Berkeley, USA
	 Stupid Fun Club is an entertainment think tank company created by Will Wright
T 1 2005 G . 2005	• Worked on prototypes for unannounced projects using C# and XNA.
July 2007 – Sept 2007	Internship – Microsoft Corporation, Redmond, USA
	• The First intern accepted to US office from a Turkish university.
Education	
May 2010	Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) - Entertainment Technologies Center, Pittsburgh, U.S.A
May 2008	Master Of Entertainment Technology (MET)
	 Created SurfaceScapes, a D&D experience on Microsoft Surface table. Presented in GDC'10 and PAX East.
	• TA for Building Virtual Worlds course.
	Sabanci University (SU), Istanbul, Turkey
	 Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Engineering (CS) TA for VA433 3D Modeling and VA434 3D Animation course.
	TA for VA455 5D Wodering and VA454 5D Animation course.
Certificates	
Aug 2020	Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera)
Oct 2020	Neural Networks and Deep Learning - DeepLearning.AI (Coursera)
Oct 2020	Improving Deep Neural Networks - DeepLearning.AI (Coursera)

Bulut Karakaya – bulutk@gmail.com

Skills

Proficient: C#, C++

Engines & Libraries: Unity, Unreal Engine 4

Version Control: Git, Perforce

Language: English (fluent), Turkish (Native)

Others: Maya, AfterEffects, PhotoShop (for programmer art)

Interests

Certified diver, tango dancer, Wing-Tsun practitioner, snowboarder and aerial acrobat. I also like games (\underline{Link}) and reading (\underline{Link}).